

Web Developer with 3.8yrs of experience, seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Angular 8, JSON, Typescript, JQuery, scss.



Current Designation: Front End Web Developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: L&T Technology Solution Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Mysoru / Mysore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mysore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: HTML5, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Angular 6, Typescript, CSS, scss, jQuery

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

## Summary

Solution-driven professional excelling in a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on the customer. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, Angular 8, JSON, fabric.js bootstrap and JavaScript. Building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to the customer's services

# Work Experience

### **L&T Technology Solution** as Front End Web Developer

Apr 2019 to Till Date

Skills & Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP, ANGULAR JS, ANGULAR 6+ , JSON, TYPESCRIPT, FABRIC.JS

Created site layout and user interface using HTML5, BOOTSTRAP and CSS3 practices.

Worked on API communication with backend team using angular http request.

Added functionality to the page by using JAVASCRIPT and ANGULAR6+.

Worked on JAVASCRIPT framework called fabric.js which is related to the canvas drawing images.

Resolve issue by debugging and analyzing the functions.

Have experience on Unit testing using Karma and Jasmine.

Good hands on JavaScript, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Angular 6+, Bootstrap.

Basic knowledge on fabric.js.

Experience in Bootstrap (responsive web design)

### Theorem Private Limited as Web Developer

Nov 2017 to Aug 2018

Skills & Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP, ANGULAR JS, ANGULAR 2 , JSON, PSD to HTML, TYPESCRIPT

Created site layout and user interface using HTML5 and CSS3 practices.

Web Development with PSD to HTML Conversion, Responsive E-mail News Letters.

Developing HTML emails and working with Harmony and Dreamweaver tool. (Epsilon Application)

Built and styled three new mobile-friendly websites and transitioned an old site into a mobile friendly version.

Testing e-mail rendering and fixing issues in listed domain using Litmus Tool (Lotus Notes, Outlook 2000 to 2016, all web domains, Android, I Phone).

Knowledge in end-to-end development of client products for advertising that is going through a life cycle which consists of Analysis, documentation, designing, testing and implementation.

Good hands on JavaScript, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS, Bootstrap, Wordpress.

Strong knowledge in using Object Oriented Programming concepts in JavaScript, working knowledge of DOM models and Strong skills of usability and accessibility with HTML, CSS.

Experience in Bootstrap (responsive web design), and Angular JS framework.

### Snipe IT Solutions as Web Developer

Aug 2016 to Nov 2017

Skills & Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, ANGULAR JS, BOOTSTRAP, JSON, WORDPRESS.

Good hands on JavaScript, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS, Bootstrap, Wordpress.

Strong knowledge in using Object Oriented Programming concepts in JavaScript, working knowledge of DOM models and Strong skills of usability and accessibility with HTML, CSS.

Experience in Bootstrap (responsive web design), and Angular JS framework.

Self-starter always inclined to learn new front-end development technologies with excellent analytical and problem solving

## **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Government Engineering College, K.R. pet in 2016

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
HTML5	5	2020	3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
BOOTSTRAP	4	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
JavaScript	ES6	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Angular 6	8	2020	1 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
JSON		2020	3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	
TypeScript				
JQUERY	3.5	2020	0 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
CSS	3	2020	3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
SCSS		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Kannada	Expert			

# **Projects**

Project Title: Chest rAI

Client: internal proect

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: This is the product based application. This project is basically related to the health Domain. The main aim of this project is to make radiologists' work easier. This is to show the abnormality of the patient x-ray and give the radiologist to control those position

Project Title: Asset Management

Client: internal project

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Mar 2018 - Aug 2018** 

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The main aim of the project is to maintain the configurations like adding events, departments, registering new employees, leave management, holiday management, etc., We can manage the employee details like their attendance, contact details, and other details.

Project Title: Travel Portal Client: Elephant tree

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2016 - Oct 2017 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Travel and tourism is the largest service industry in India. It provides heritage, cultural, medical, business, and sports tourism. The main the objective of this sector is to develop and promote tourism, maintain competitiveness of India as a tourist destination and improve and expand existing Tourism products to ensure employment generation and economic growth. In this section, we provide information about various tourist destinations, modes of travel, accommodation, and approved travel agents.

#### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: SC Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time